<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Career Log]]></title><description><![CDATA[A log of career activities]]></description><link>https://scottellis64.github.io</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 14:49:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scottellis64.github.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Meeting with Ken]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Isaac suggested in our one-on-one yesterday that I meet with Ken to communicate what I&#8217;ve been up to.  Isaac mentioned that there are grumblings that Ken has visibility into what Filipe has been doing, but nothing where I am concerned.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It was a positive meeting and he just wants to know what I will be doing with my time so he can plan for his project.  After I meet with Rajeev today I will come up with an estimate of the time I&#8217;ll need to perform all the remaining work and with that determine how I will split my time between Algo and the Installer.  I&#8217;ll connect with Ken tomorrow post-scrum and come up with a plan that splits my time so I can communicate that with both he and Rajeev.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://scottellis64.github.io/2017/07/18/Meeting-with-Ken.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottellis64.github.io/2017/07/18/Meeting-with-Ken.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Ellis]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 18, 2017]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Yesterday</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Created a production build for the op-installer that combines the client, server and auth-server into one zip file with these features:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>provides its own gulp file and package.json that provides all that is needed to build (npm install) and run the application (npm start) in production mode.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>temporarily creates a default deployment so that the install UI works without manual intervention (previously had to create a test deployment by hand)</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Met with Filipe, Josh and Wenlong to discuss rest api end point naming and questions concerning configuration import.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Today</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Have to take a few days to get the Algo group on track.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Meeting with Rajeev at 11 to determine the depth and breadth of my remaining tasks</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Then attending group status meeting at 11:30</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Creating/updating RTC tasks to reflect the work I&#8217;ve done to date on the op-installer (apologies for not keeping them up to date&#8212;&#8203;will work at dillegence)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Putting together a presentation showing the makeup of the typescript auth-server.  Will meet with the team some time either this week or next to discuss.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Going forward</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>With the build and deployment work done, moving on to doing some op-installer UI work.  Taking on the <em>Choose Deployment</em> page that appears after login.  Currently login takes the user to a default deployment called <em>testInstall</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Will update READMEs to reflect current processes for running and deploying project</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Create some quick diagrams to show how the op-installer modules fit together to create one unit in both production and dev.  Investigate how this diagram can be displayed in the projects README.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>]]></description><link>https://scottellis64.github.io/2017/07/18/July-18-2017.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottellis64.github.io/2017/07/18/July-18-2017.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Ellis]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tuesday, December 14th 2016]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="literalblock">
<div class="title">Dev Ops Workshop</div>
<div class="content">
<pre>Its all about the docker image.
Learned about working IBM GitHub and creating issues and resolving.
I'm working on setting up Tomcat 7 on Centos 7 with ssl enabled and Java 8
Had some trouble with all this since Docker is not something I know through and through
but I have a lot of experience with Linux at this point, and my VM mechanics help with getting things to work.
Hoping tomorrow I get a lot done.</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="literalblock">
<div class="title">Chris one-one</div>
<div class="content">
<pre>.Todos
* Prioritize getting stories and tasks created and estimated
  - Get acceptance criteria done and make sure QE has enough to create test plans
* Rename UCF Connector tab to UCF Connector / RCoC Q1
* Modify team members:
  - Remove Ken as build engineer
  - Add Mark as QE
* Add one or two sprints to the project
* Identify one or two stories to get started on before leaving for Christmas break
* Questionnaire is a nice-to-have; prioritize UCF Connector
* Get UCF connector story/task into implementing state
* Review stories 52328, 52308 and 52309 to see if they can be finished off after the new REST TDI connector is implemented
* Consider adding a task for converting existing file connector-implemented stories/tasks to using the new REST TDI connector
* Update scheme task or story??

.Kick off
* Scrum kick off meeting is set for Thursday at 4
* Talk about which stories to work on
* Schedule stand up for two times a week and pick a day and time that works for everyone

NOTE: UCF will likely merge into the larger RCoC team

.Chris' suggestions for working with RCoC group (Rajeev and ?)
* Do quality work--there are high expectations of me coming in
* Communicate effectively and often--don't let problems queue up without letting folks know what is going on
* Rajeev is easy going, but members are emotionally vested in their product (implication is, choose my words carefully, be diplomatic)
* Provide very good input
* Keep promises
* Sift into the mix gradually
* Don't overstretch

.Random notes from one on one meeting
* There will be one week left after vacation for sprint 2
* In betwixt all this, I need to be ready to help out if needed with OpenPages, either to offer guidance or to jump in and make fixes</pre>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://scottellis64.github.io/2016/12/14/Tuesday-December-14th-2016.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottellis64.github.io/2016/12/14/Tuesday-December-14th-2016.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Ellis]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Notes from 12/13/2016 One-on-one meeting with Chris]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Updating will cause a change log—that can cause confusion</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Goal before kickoff
	For testing, authentication, clarify what is success</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Change dates
	RCOC is later in march for release
	Go well into February for Development
	Add one or two sprints</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Rename UCF Connector to UCF Connector / RCoC Q1</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Add team members, will need to add Rajeev (not right away)
QE - add Mark</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Identify one or two stories to get started on</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If we can get Questionnaire started, that’s nice
Basic requirements</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Review 52328, 52308 and 52309 and see if we can finish these off using the new REST TDI connector
Maybe need a task to convert these two from file to api calls</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Update scheme task or story</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One week when we come back to finish sprint 2</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>RCOC -
Embed cognos reports
Need visibility to GitHub RCoC from RTC</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Scrum:
What stories to work on?
Acceptance criteria needs to be locked down
Schedule on a regular scrum time and frequency (suggest 2 times a week)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Eventually UCF will merge with RCoC meeting</p>
</div>
<div class="sidebarblock">
<div class="content">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As team lead have to work with team members
 	— Michelle, from quality</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Balance expectation and what is actually completed</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Need to multitask</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Simplest solution first, then work on the better solution</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Do quality work
Communicate
Rajeev is easy going
they have a lot of emotion tied to their product
provide very good input
keep promises
They have high expectations of me
Gradually come in and help out
don’t overstretch</p>
</div>
<hr>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Might need my help with features in OP environment available
Need to be able to jump in and fix</p>
</div>
<hr>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://scottellis64.github.io/2016/12/14/Notes-from-12132016-One-on-one-meeting-with-Chris.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottellis64.github.io/2016/12/14/Notes-from-12132016-One-on-one-meeting-with-Chris.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Ellis]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[User Dashboard Design Review]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I presented my design to the OpenPages UI team today&#8212;&#8203;I put quite a bit of work into it.  I had prepared several UML class diagrams detailing the entity relationships, and prepared xsd schemas to describe the format of the dojo data stores.  Some of the diagrams had a lot of content, so I was nervous about showing the first of them.  When I did, Chris had a look on his face and stopped me to ask why it was so complicated, and went on to say that when he looks at diagrams like that, he doesn&#8217;t understand them at all.  He prefers code snippets.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So this is interesting.  Complicated&#8212;&#8203;this has been the most enduring criticism of my code and designs since I started at IBM, tracing back to my first feature, the Actor Picker, when Mike Poole thought that the solution I came up with was way over the top.  Mike has gone out of his way to point out that he thinks that John Owen is a superstar and that he and I were just ok.  I&#8217;m not sure where he stands on that today.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But now here is Chris parroting those same words.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In listening to the session playback later (I&#8217;m backwriting this post on December 7), I&#8217;m disappointed by the number of times I say "uh".  I need to be better prepared.  However, I am not prepared because I was busy and barely finished preparing my design diagrams and slides.  I have to be better at presenting.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>John Owen asks me a question in the meeting and says essentially that we should have pushed back and took away from the complexity of what was delivered by only having a single wiget per panel.  This is irritating because everyone involved knew about the design and there was plenty of time to push back then.  Now I have to listen to this while presenting what I consider to be incredibly good work.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Keep in mind that this feature is now delivered.  Yes, it went right up to the buzzer but it is done and is working extremely well.  And by its very nature the feature is complex and it was an accomplishment to get this done and have it be as solid as it is.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I can&#8217;t help but think that my success in this is causing John and maybe even Chris some discomfort.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In regards to the complexity of diagrams, here are some things that were said:</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>Chris: I can&#8217;t read this</code></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>John: The json is probably a much more consise view of the same information</code></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>Kate: No, but Chris, I like jumped right in and added features to this.  This is making it seem more complicated than it is</code></p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://scottellis64.github.io/2016/12/07/User-Dashboard-Design-Review.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottellis64.github.io/2016/12/07/User-Dashboard-Design-Review.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Ellis]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Second Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Hello, my name is Sue.  Now you gonna die!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://scottellis64.github.io/2016/12/06/A-Second-Post.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottellis64.github.io/2016/12/06/A-Second-Post.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Ellis]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Back Date This]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Try to back date this!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I really think it is going to work.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://scottellis64.github.io/2012/02/10/Back-Date-This.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottellis64.github.io/2012/02/10/Back-Date-This.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Ellis]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>